Finding Aid for the Synanon Foundation Records LSC.0342
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Film (to eventually be deleted)
  - Staff game - Tomales Bay -, 1967. (Box 586)
  - Jack's video game -, 1967. (Box 586)
  - Teenage game. (Box 586)
  - House on the beach - reel 2 of 2. (Box 587)
  - House on the beach - reel 1 of 2. (Box 587)
  - Female boots - w.p. - outs - pic. -, 1972. (Box 587)
  - Five - orig. & w.p. - outs - pic. -, 1972. (Box 587)
  - People ranch - extra copy. (Box 587)
  - People's ranch - orig. - outs - pic. -, 1972. (Box 587)
  - Alcohol, drugs or alternatives - A/V - #54. (Box 587)
  - How place - orig. film - Sounds of Synanon. (Box 587)
  - Synanon on film - w.p. - composite track - pic. -, 1972. (Box 719, Item 22 and 23)
    The original container held one reel of magnetic audio (now item 22 in box 719) and a 16mm workprint (now item 23 in box 719). Please note the magnetic audio has vinegar syndrome and has been removed by Preservation for treatment as of 6/24/2015.
  - History lecture # 1 - D.D. Harvey - AV #38. (Box 588)
  - CBS jazz scenes - Sounds of Synanon - duplicate. (Box 588)
  - Wedding - w.p. - outs & trims - pic. - 1972 (1 of 2). (Box 588)
  - Wedding - w.p. - outs & trims - pic. - (2 of 2)., 1972 (Box 588)
  - Synanon on film - A & B roll - pic. -, 1972. (Box 588)
  - KTVU commercial - master material - A & B roll - orig. - w.p. - sound track -, 1973. (Box 588)
  - Magic flute - w.p. - pic. - 16mm. - black and white -, 1973 (Box 588)
  - To slay a white horse. (Box 588)
  - Jitney bunch - w.p. - outs - pic. -, 1972. (Box 589)
  - Tannersville - outtakes - release print -, 1968. (Box 589)
  - Kid's summer camp - w.p. - pic. -, 1972. (Box 589)
  - Movie print of wedding videotape. (Box 589)
  - Synanon on film - master material - A-roll - mag track & w.p. -, 1972. (Box 589)
  - Synanon - cassette #2 - master material - A-roll - pic. -, 1973. (Box 589)
  - Synanon - cassette #2 - B-roll master material - pic. -, 1973. (Box 589)
  - Synanon cassette #2 - w.p. - pic. -, 1973. (Box 589)
  - 4H - w.p. outs - pic. -, 1972. (Box 589)
  - 116c. (Box 590)
  - 116a. (Box 590)
  - 116b. (Box 590)
  - 116d. (Box 590)
  - People ranch - voice mag track - speeded up n.g. -, 1971. (Box 590)
  - People ranch - w.p. - outs - pics. -, 1972. (Box 590)
  - Hatchery - orig. - outtakes - pic. -, 1972. (Box 590)
  - People ranch - orig. - outs - pic. -, 1972. (Box 590)
  - People ranch - orig. - outs - pic. - (1 of 2)., 1972 (Box 590)
  - People ranch - orig. - outs - pic. - (2 of 2)., 1972 (Box 590)
  - Synanon lecture #1 - Mag track ret. (Box 590)
  - [Untitled recording ]., April 21, 1967 (Box 591)
  - Robert Kennedy remembered A/V #43. (Box 591)
  - Miracle on the beach - - S.M., 1963 (Box 591)
  - Synanon in prison - - 20th century., March 13, 1966 (Box 591)
  - To slay a white horse. (Box 591)
  - House on the beach; Oversize flat box. (Box 592)
  - House on the beach - A/V #47. (Box 592)
  - House on the beach - A/V. (Box 593)
  - House on the beach - duplicate #297. (Box 593)
  - House on the beach - Rediffusion Television Limited - Denis Mitchell, director -; Oversize flat box., 1965 (Box 593)
  - S. o F [Synanon on film] - w.p. - outs - pic. -, 1972. (Box 594)
  - People ranch - 16mm. - voice & music track - - short version., 1972 (Box 594)
  - Deputies - outtakes - orig. & w.p. - pic. -; Oversize flat box., 1972 (Box 594)
  - The most adult game, parts 1 & 2 - KRON-TV - S.F. -, 1967. (Box 595)
  - Synanon on film - orig. - w.p. & mag track - pic. -, 1972. (Box 595)
  - Synanon on film - orig. - A & B roll - pic. -; Oversize flat box., 1972 (Box 595)
  - House on the beach (2 of 2). (Box 596)
  - The most adult game, parts 1 & 2 - KRON-TV - S.F. -; Oversize flat box., 1967 (Box 596)
  - House on the beach (1 of 2). (Box 596)
  - People ranch - orig. & w.p. -, 1972. (Box 597)
  - The neighborhood gets a fix. (Box 597)
  - Annual report to stockholders -; Oversize flat box., 1967 (Box 597)
  - People ranch - voice & music track - 16 mm. mag. - 1972. (Box 598)
  - Synaon on film August - A, B & C rolls - composite track & w.p. -; Oversize flat box., 1972 (Box 598)
  - House on the beach - #332; Oversize flat box. (Box 599)
  - House on the beach - #293. (Box 599)
  - House on the beach - - #1., 1965 (Box 599)
  - Home movie of a boat trip; Oversize flat box. (Box 600)
  - Neighborhood gets a fix. (Box 600)
  - Synanon on film - March - Master material - A-roll - composite mag track -, 1972. (Box 600)
- Films
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains processed audiovisual materials. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - The Synanon Wedding Festival: Composite Print, 1972; yrlsc_342_570_001; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Color faded. Slightly warped. (Box 570, Case 1)
    CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    Scope and Contents
    Synanon archive #311. Synanon Films label on can: "Title: The Wedding Festival / No: 45-5 / Property of: Synanon Foundation Inc. / Running time: 16 min. / Feet: 606 / Color / Sound" Lid also labeled: "Duplicate audio/visual of #58 / Wedding Festival" and "Archives Film Circulation Library" Side of can labeled: "45/5 Synanon Wedding Festival" Festival for mass wedding held in Walker Creek Ranch on August 6, 1972, with 72 couples involved. Includes Chuck and Betty Dederich.
  - Swimming Slobs: Mag Camera Original Outtakes, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_570_002; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:02:46) 100 feet; Base scratches throughout, but emulsion is clear. Tape splices are all a little sloppy with gaps in between. (Box 570, Case 2)
    Synanon archive #249. Side of can labeled: "A-34 - Swimming Slobs - Orig. & W.P. - Outs - Pic. - 1972" Group in swimming pool. Woman diving into pool. Shots of rippling water.
  - Swimming Slobs: Work Print Outtakes, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_570_003; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:02:05) 75 feet; Some tape residue remains. Redox blemishes throughout, likely caused by original tape. Some splices have overlapping film and some have gaps. (Box 570, Case 3)
    Synanon archive #249. Side of can labeled: "A-34 - Swimming Slobs - Orig. & W.P. - Outs - Pic. - 1972" People in swimming pool. Might duplicate or just have very similar footage to yrlsc_342_570_002.
  - Professional Weekend: Work Print Outtakes, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_570_004; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:04:51) 175 feet; Some broken perfs at splices, likely caused by guillotine splicer. Redox blemishes throughout, likely caused by original tape. Kodak stock, but edge information difficult to read to determine any more specific than that. (Box 570, Case 4)
    Synanon archive #250. Side of can labeled: "A-31 Professional Weekend - WP - Outs - Pic - 72 -" People gathered outside, likely at one of Synanon's ranches in Marin. Arm wrestling on the ground. Standing in a circle and holding hands. Sign for "Synanon 4-H Club" and "Welcome Conventioneers"
  - Professional Weekend: Work Print Outtakes, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_570_005; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:02:05) 75 feet; Uncut film. Kodak stock, but edge information difficult to read to determine any more specific than that. (Box 570, Case 5)
    Synanon archive #250. Side of can labeled: "A-31 Professional Weekend - WP - Outs - Pic - 72 -" Driving around on ranch.
  - San Francisco Anniversary: Camera Original Outtakes, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_570_006; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:10:25) 375 feet; Some tape residue remains. Redox blemishes throughout, likely caused by original tape. Tape splices frequently have gaps in between them. (Box 570, Case 6)
    Synanon archive #252. Side of can labeled: "A-13 - S.F. Anniversary - Orig. - Outs - Pic - 1972" Appears to be outtakes related to Synanon celebrating an anniversary of collaborating with NL Industries in San Francisco. NL Industries gave Synanon their old paint factory location in 1970, to which Synanon moved from their Seawall location in San Francisco. Film features press conference with Channel 7 microphones and KQED cameras visible. Wooden house with broken windows and sign "People Live Here." People dancing and band performing in elaborate costumes. Signs shown: "NLI + Synanon = A Nice Thing for San Francisco", "You Made it Possible - NL Industries / Synanon", Synanon: Recycling People and Buildings" Channel 5 microphone and KPIX 5 logo visible during production shots.
  - Children of Synanon: Composite Print, 1968; yrlsc_342_570_007; Lester, Howard; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Footage starts abruptly after leader. Might be missing footage at head. Very scratched throughout, though worse predominantly at head. Tear near tail with poor condition tape splice repair - left during inspection. (Box 570, Case 7)
    Synanon archive #274. Synanon Films label on can: "Title: Children of Synanon / No: 27-5 / by Howard Lester / Running time: 15:34 / Black and white / Sound" Side of can labeled: "27/5 - Children of Synanon" Documentary on children living at Synanon and going to school. Playing the Game. Directed by Howard Lester with assistance from Chick Strand.
  - Children of Synanon: Composite Print, 1968; yrlsc_342_570_008; Lester, Howard; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Significantly scratched on both emulsion and base sides. Dull residue on one side of original wind - maybe mold? (Box 570, Case 8)
    Synanon archive #273. Palmer Film Services label on can: "Title: Children of Synanon - 1968 / Property of: Synanon Foundation, Inc. / [...] / Running time: 15:34 / Black and white" Lid also labeled: "Archives Film Circulation Library" Side of can labeled: "H26/4 - Children of Synanon" Documentary on children living at Synanon and going to school. Playing the Game. Directed by Howard Lester with assistance from Chick Strand.
  - The Synanon People Ranch: Composite Print, 1972; yrlsc_342_570_009; Hilberman, David, 1911-2007; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; More scratched on emulsion side than base. Yellow residue (tape of some kind?) at head underlying labeling part of original leader. Some has been removed, but most remains. Looks stable and likely won't affect transfer. (Box 570, Case 9)
    Palmer Film Services label on can: "Title: Synanon - The People Ranch (1972) / Property of: Synanon Foundation, Inc. / [...] / Running time: 16:30 / Feet: 600 / Black and White / Sound" Punch card with title, customer (Synanon), and order number information about film from Consolidated Film Industries included within can. Promotional film depicting life in Synanon ranch.
  - Mobile Dental Unit: Camera Original Outtakes, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_570_010; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:10:25) 375 feet; Some residue from original tape remains. Some new tape splices have slightly overlapping film. (Box 570, Case 10)
    Synanon archive #251. Side of can labeled: "A-35 - Mobil Dental Unit - Orig. - Outs - Pic - 1972" University of Southern California Mobile Dental Clinic. Dentistry in action. Includes dentistry on piglets.
  - The Synanon Wedding Festival: Composite Print, 1972; yrlsc_342_570_011; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Color faded. Uncut film. Warping throughout. Base scratching worse than emulsion scratching (and both worse at head). (Box 570, Case 11)
    Synanon Films label on can: "Title: The Wedding Festival / No: 45-7 / Property of: Synanon Foundation Inc. / Running time: 16 min. / Feet: 606 / Color / Sound" Side of can labeled: "45/7 Synanon Wedding Festival" Festival for mass wedding held in Walker Creek Ranch on August 6, 1972, with 72 couples involved. Includes Chuck and Betty Dederich.
  - "Instant Guide to Synanon" Track 2 Voice: Fullcoat Mag, 1973; yrlsc_342_573_001; 1 sound recordings (1 16mm full-coat mag; Duration: 00:09:01) 325 feet; Significantly warped with vinegar syndrome. (Box 573, Case 1)
    Synanon archive #157. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled: "D-13 - Instant Guide - Orig. - Master Material - Mag. Track 1, 2 & 3 - 1973" Notes throughout, including "May I help", "Detroit - S.F. - S.M. - Oak", "A-18", "A-16", "375,000", "Where located", and "Plus one"
  - The Synanon People Ranch: Titles: Camera Original, 1972; yrlsc_342_573_002; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:04:51) 175 feet; Slightly sticky emulsion. Warping near tail, including section crumpled into center of original reel. (Box 573, Case 2)
    Synanon archive #195a-b. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled: "Titles (working) - A Synanon Film & Copyright 1972-1973 Orig." Title: "The Synanon People Ranch / Copyright 1972, Synanon Foundation, Inc. All Rights Reserved" followed by sequence of just copyright line. Black and white text printed onto color film stock.
  - "Synanon Law Lecture #2: Dan Garrett": Composite Reversal Print (Reel 1 of 2), 1973; yrlsc_342_573_003; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:30:33) 1100 feet; Some rough edges, but no perfs broken or torn. Small tears in soundtrack edge approx. 300' into reel. Occasional grease pencil marks. Some redox blemishes at tail. (Box 573, Case 3)
    Synanon archive #158a. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled on lid and side: "A-40-2 - [...] Lec. #2 - Orig. - Pic. - 16mm - B&W - 1973" Video to film transfer. Starts with wide shot of stage "Synanon Research University" and then all medium close-up on lecturer. Likely image component to yrslc_342_576_010.
  - "Synanon Law Lecture #2: Dan Garrett": Composite Reversal Print (Reel 2 of 2), 1973; yrlsc_342_573_004; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:07:38) 275 feet; Hand-drawn sync mark at head. Uncut film. (Box 573, Case 4)
    Synanon archive #158b. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled on lid and side: "A-40-2 - [...] Lec. #2 - Orig. - Pic. - 16mm - B&W - 1973" Video to film transfer. Starts with snow and calibration light. Finishes lecture and ends with wide shot and back of crowd. Likely image component to yrlsc_342_720_015.
  - Santa Monica Wedding: Camera Original, 1973; yrlsc_342_573_005; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film); Emulsion slightly sticking to itself during unwinding. (Box 573, Case 5)
    Synanon archive #156a. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled: "CFI Original - Do Not Project" and "Santa Monica Wedding - Orig. - Pic. - 1973" Likely film of Synanon wedding ceremony in Santa Monica in 1973, one year after the main Synanon Wedding Festival in northern California in 1972. Group on beach at golden hour - very beautiful! Procession on beach outside Del Mar building. Gathered on top of Del Mar building: couples embracing, kissing. Inside, sitting in circle. Ceremony inside with mostly floral print clothes. Many out of focus shots.
  - Santa Monica Wedding: Audio, 1973; yrlsc_342_573_006; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape) (Box 573, Case 6)
    Synanon archive #156b. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled: "CFI Original - Do Not Project" and "Santa Monica Wedding - Orig. - Pic. - 1973" Box labeled: "No content" but unclear if the tape is actually blank.
  - Santa Monica Wedding: Audio, 1973; yrlsc_342_573_007; 1 sound recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape) (Box 573, Case 7)
    Synanon archive #156c. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled: "CFI Original - Do Not Project" and "Santa Monica Wedding - Orig. - Pic. - 1973" Box labeled: "No content" but unclear if the tape is actually blank.
  - Upward Mobility: Mag Camera Original Outtakes, 1973; yrlsc_342_573_008; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:15:16) 550 feet; Segments originally loosely taped together, now properly tape spliced. Some dusty tape residue remains. Redox blemishes occasionally throughout due to original tape. Segment of mag stripe (single perf) in first half of reel, Kodak TXR 52 Safety stock. (Box 573, Case 8)
    Synanon archive #155. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled: "A-10 - Upward Mobility - Orig. - Pic. - 16mm - B&W - 1973" Tail leader: "Tail (PFH) - Synanon - 'A10 CED-SM'" Head leader: "(Roll #1) - Synanon - Head (PFH)" Young men receiving and giving haircuts. Sitting in group, possibly a Game? Exercising on beach outside Del Mar building.
  - Bay to Breakers: Work Print, 1973; yrlsc_342_573_009; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:22:13) 800 feet; All image is black and white, so unsure if Eastman ECO film (color) is just print-through or black and white image has been printed onto color stock. (Box 573, Case 9)
    Synanon archive #177a. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled: "A-41 Bay to Breakers - W.P. - Pic. - 16MM - B&W - 1973" Synanon runs Bay to Breakers in San Francisco in 1973. First 100' appear to be print of color original yrlsc_342_722_007. Latter 700' appear to be print of color original yrlsc_342_721_001.
  - Synanon History Lecture #1: Work Print, 1973; yrlsc_342_573_010; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:27:46) 1000 feet; Harvey lecturing sections are video to film transfer with variable density soundtrack printed onto double perf film. Some indentations between sprocket holes indicate misaligned projection at some point. Big tear approximately 800 feet into reel previously repaired with opaque off-white tape. Some isolated instances of broken perfs. Splices in general are sloppy, have gaps. Grease pencil markings at head. (Box 573, Case 10)
    Synanon archive #154. Inside Consolidated Film Industries box labeled: "A-40-I - Synanon History Lec #I - [...] - W.P. - Outtakes - Pic. - 16mm - B&W - 1973 - Audience shots" Video to film transfer of lecture on Synanon history at Synanon Research University in 1973. Intercuts lecturing with shots of audience (appear to be originally shot on film). Likely workprint for yrlsc_342_582_009 and yrlsc_342_582_010.
  - Instant Guide to Synanon: Composite Print, 1973; yrlsc_342_575_001; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:01) 325 feet; Color faded. Original tape splice has gap in between. Many perf tears near head, some repaired with edge tape, others (less severe) not. Some indentations between perfs throughout indicate possible misalignment of projector sprockets. (Box 575, Case 1)
    Synanon archive #318. In can with Synanon Films label: "Title: Instant Guide to Synanon / Running time: 8:45 / Feet 313 / Color" and "Audio visual #17 duplicate." Side of can labeled: "115/16 - Instant Guide to Synanon" Promotional film for Synanon styled as a Q&A.
  - Instant Guide to Synanon: Composite Print, 1973; yrlsc_342_575_002; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:09:01) 325 feet; Color faded. Reinforced cement splice with tape. Some edge repair tape previously applied at head to fix torn perfs. Bloop patch at cement splice fell off during inspection. (Box 575, Case 2)
    Synanon archive #319. Inside can with Synanon Films label: "Title: Instant Guide to Synanon / No. 52-3 / Property of Synanon Foundation Inc. / Running time: 8:45 min / Feet: 313 / Color" and "Duplicate #17 - Instant Guide to (S)" Promotional film for Synanon styled as a Q&A.
  - Camera and Film Tests: Mag Camera Original, circa 1972; yrlsc_342_575_003; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:13:53) 500 feet; Base side significantly scratched. Switches between silent double perf and mag stripe single perf. Some broken perfs at splice of first switch. Also printed on edge: "EKco H 9/72" (Box 575, Case 3)
    Synanon archive #271. Side of can labeled: "Camera + Film Tests - Color (Aug 72)" Camera and film development tests mostly shot outside in daylight, on the street or in a parking lot. Some shots inside. Mostly of people holding slates or grey cards and a little bit walking around. Handwritten labels in between each segment indicate development changes, such as "Dev. normal," "Push 1 stop," or "Push 2 stops"
  - Behind the Scenes at Synanon: Composite Print, circa 1965; yrlsc_342_575_004; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:05:33) 200 feet; Occasional torn perfs throughout. Scratching worse at head. Tape splice with significant gap left. (Box 575, Case 4)
    Synanon archive #307. In can with Synanon Films label: "Title: Behind the Scenes at Synanon - Trailer 'Synanon' / No. 17-3 / Property of Synanon Foundation, Inc. / Running time: 5 min / Feet: 178' / Black and white" and "Duplicate of #17-4 #3." Side of can labeled: "H 15/3 Behind the Scenes at Synanon" Behind the scenes of 1965 Synanon feature film. Features Synanon House, actors from the movie, and Chuck Dederich.
  - The Synanon Wedding Festival: Composite Reversal Print, 1972; yrlsc_342_575_005; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Beautiful color! Base scratching throughout. (Box 575, Case 5)
    Synanon archive #312. In can with Palmer Film Services label: "Title: Synanon Wedding Festival - 1972 / Property of Synanon Foundation, Inc. / [...] / Running time: 16: / Feet: 589' / Color" and "Duplicate Wedding Festival #58" Side of can labeled: "45/2 Synanon Wedding Festival" Festival for mass wedding held in Walker Creek Ranch on August 6, 1972, with 72 couples involved. Includes Chuck and Betty Dederich.
  - The Synanon People Ranch: Composite Print, 1972; yrlsc_342_575_006; Hilberman, David, 1911-2007; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Scratching throughout, otherwise in good condition. (Box 575, Case 6)
    Synanon archive #285. Inside can with Palmer Film Services: "Title: Synanon's People Ranch / Property of: "Synanon Foundation, Inc. / [...] / Running time: 16: / Feet: 606' / Black and white." Side of can labeled: "40/5 People Ranch" Promotional film depicting life in Synanon ranch.
  - The Synanon People Ranch: Composite Print, 1972; yrlsc_342_575_007; Hilberman, David, 1911-2007; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Occasional torn perfs throughout. Some scratches and minor damage around cement splice. (Box 575, Case 7)
    Synanon archive #287. Inside can with Palmer Film Services label: "Title: Synanon, The People Ranch (1972) / Property of Synanon Foundation, Inc. / [...] / Running time: 16:30 / Feet; 600 / Black and white." Side of can labeled: "103/14 People Ranch" Promotional film depicting life in Synanon ranch.
  - Children of Synanon: Composite Print, 1968; yrlsc_342_575_008; Lester, Howard; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Minor emulsion scratches and slightly stiff film. (Box 575, Case 8)
    Synanon archive #301. Note on can: "The green protective leader broke off this film. It needs a new one. " and "Duplicate of audio visual #4." Side of can labeled: "H26/3 Children of Synanon" Bottom of can labeled: "Children of Synanon by Howard Lester #27-3 / 71-042 / Howard Lester - [...]" and "Projectionist: The academy leader is part of the film and is intended to be seen. Begin projection before academy leader." Documentary on children living at Synanon and going to school. Playing the Game. Directed by Howard Lester with assistance from Chick Strand.
  - Children of Synanon: Composite Print, 1968; yrlsc_342_575_009; Lester, Howard; 1 motion picture film (1 16mm film; Duration: 00:16:40) 600 feet; Film slightly warping and brittle. Made crackling noise as the film settled during unwinding. (Box 575, Case 9)